tsu
突
ppa
っ走
shi
tte
って
ku
く
ze
ぜ
GLORY
DAYS!
Feixin Unit captain, remember this.
（王賁(おうほん)）飛信(ひしん)隊隊長 覚えておけ
My name is Wang Ben.
（王賁）我が名は王賁
Wang Ben?
（信）王賁？
Wang...
“王”…
“王”！
Wang?!
Yes.
ああ
お前の大好きな あの王騎(おうき)の一族
The same family as your beloved Wang Qi.
分家の王騎とは違い
Unlike Wang Qi, who was of a branch family,
I, Wang Ben, have inherited the blood of the main branch of the Wang family.
王一族の総本家を継ぐ王賁だ
Survive scenes of carnage together with everyone.
（王騎）
皆と共に修羅場をくぐりなさい
You have potential, Xin.
素質はありますよ 信
A Third Force
What the hell was with that Wang Ben youngster?!
（田永(でんえい)）
なんだ あの王賁とかいう若造は！
We're ants?
俺たちは蟻(あり)だと？
We should just be quiet and follow orders?!
黙って命令に従ってりゃいいだと？
Fuck you!
ふざけやがって！
Shen Chief
Long You
But still... not only could we not refute him...
（竜有(りゅうゆう)）
それなのに 俺たち
反論するどころか…
Just one shout from that huge old man made us friggin' stand at attention.
（去亥(きょがい)）でっけえ
じいさんのひと声で―
Shen Chief
Qu Hai
気をつけまで
しちまうなんて
Aw man. He gave us our first reminder in a while.
（松左(しょうさ)）まいったな…
久々に 思い知らされちまった
That there is a gigantic wall we can't climb over
俺たちとヤツら士族との間には―
between us and those warrior families.
超えられねえ でっけえ壁が
あったってことを
（昂(こう)）でも…
But, that Yufeng Unit was pretty cool, wasn't it?
（昂）
カッコよかったな 玉鳳(ぎょくほう)隊って
What'd you just say, Ang?
（尾平(びへい)）
昂… 今 何つった？ てめえ
あっ… ご… ごめんなさい
I-I'm sorry.
Can't you tell how everyone's feeling right now?!
お前 この場の空気が読めねえのか
（信）やめとけよ 尾平
Knock it off, Wei Ping.
It's okay, isn't it? He just said what he honestly thought.
別にいいじゃねえか
思ってることを正直に言ったって
Those Yufeng Unit guys definitely were shiny and cool.
確かに 玉鳳隊のヤツらは
キラキラしてて カッコよかったぜ
なあ？ 昂
（昂）う… うん
Right, Ang?
You wanna become like them?
あいつらみてえになりてえか？
（昂）えっ？
If we build up military achievements like crazy, we will.
でっけえ武功を上げまくりゃ
なれるぞ お前も士族に
You'll become warrior class, too.
M-Me? Warrior class?
お… おいらが士族に？
Song Zuo!
松左！ 今更 壁なんて
くだらねえこと言ってんなよ
Don't say bullshit about "walls" like that after all we've been through.
That's nothing but an excuse, ain't it?
そんなの ただの言い訳だろう
（松左）言い訳？
Excuse?
Yeah.
ああ とどのつまり―
When it comes down to it, we were just pressured by them and lowered our heads.
俺たちは ヤツらに圧倒されて
下向いちまっただけだ
We suddently took a hit to our pride, and lost our morale.
いきなり ガツンと１発やられて
戦意喪失しちまったんだよ
You've gotta be kidding me!
冗談じゃねえぞ！
I don't give a shit if he is General Wang Qi's relative!
王騎将軍の
親戚だか何だか知らねえが
Like hell I'm just gonna sit quietly!
このまま黙ってられっかよ！
今度は こっちの番だ
Now, it's our turn!
やられた分
きっちり やり返すぞ てめえら！
We'll pay them back for every insult they gave us!
Pay them back?
やり返すって…
でも 味方同士で戦っちゃ 罪に…
But fighting between allies is a crime...
（尾平）分かんねえか？ 昂
Don't you get it, Ang?
By pay them back, he means that we'll render achievements before the Yufeng Unit does.
“やり返す”ってのは―
この次は 玉鳳隊のヤツらより先に
俺たちが手柄を上げるって意味だ
（崇原(すうげん)）しかし 問題は
どうやって手柄を上げるかだ
But the problem is, how do we render achievements?
In order to outflank the Yufeng Unit, who are all riding on horses,
（崇原）全員が
馬に乗ってる玉鳳隊を出し抜くには
何か特別な作戦が必要だぞ
we're going to need some sort of special strategy.
That's what we'll come up with!
それをこれから考えるんだよ
I have one strategy.
（魯延(ろえん)）ひとつ作戦があるぞい
（信）魯延じい
Old Man Lü Yan.
Though it's a rigorous strategy that only we can accomplish...
（魯延）わしらにしか
できぬ 過酷な作戦じゃがのぅ
Rigorous strategy?
過酷な作戦？
Did you hear, Lord Wang Ben?
（番陽(ばんよう)）
聞かれましたか？ 王賁さま
先日 出会った飛信隊 なんでも―
It would seem that the Feixin Unit we met yesterday
went missing last night, and other units have been searching for them.
あの夜から行方が分からなくなり
ほかの部隊が捜し回っているとか
It appears that they really responded to us taking that achievement and showing the difference between us.
（番陽）
我らに手柄を取られたうえに―
力の差を見せつけられて
よほど こたえたのでしょう
Do you think they've returned to the
country so they can plow their fields?
今ごろ 田舎に戻って 田畑を
耕しているのではありませんか？
（尾平）いてー！
何やってんだ…
What're you doing?
Ow... Damn wild dog...
いててて… 野良犬め
いきなり かみつきやがって
Suddenly biting me like that...
ンンッ… 尾平のヤツ
Geez, Wei Ping!
Get lost, you big mutt!
うせろ 犬公！
Here they come.
来るぞ 魏(ぎ)のヤツらが
The Wei guys...
（信）よし 魯延じい 聞かせてくれ
その過酷な作戦ってのをよ
Okay, Old Man Lü Yan, let's hear it.
That rigorous strategy of yours.
The State of Wei Army is gathering up scattered soldiers and organizing camps.
魏国の軍は―
いったん散らばっていた兵を集めて
陣地を整えようとしておる
As we want to render big achievements, a large number of enemies gathering in one place will be convenient for us.
大勢の敵が集まるのは―
大きな手柄を上げたいと
思っておるわしらには好都合じゃが
But in exchange, the number of enemies we will need to fight before reaching the headquarters will be great.
その分 本陣に たどりつくまでに
戦わねばならん敵の数も多くなり
So as we are rather few in number, we may be at a disadvantage.
少ない人数で
攻め込む わしらには不利でもある
But fortunately, the mist is thick in this area,
幸い この辺りは 霧が深いうえに
打ち続く戦で命を落とした者たちの
屍(しかばね)が放置されたままじゃ
and as a result of the constant fighting, the corpses of the fallen have been left laying around.
By blending in with the corpses in that mist,
わしらは この霧と屍に紛れながら
敵と刃(やいば)を交えることなく
敵の本陣に 忍び寄ることができる
we will be able to creep our way to the enemy headquarters without ever crossing swords with the enemy.
However, to slip in between rotting corpses,
ただし 腐乱した屍に紛れるのは
we will need to be prepared for pain even greater than fighting the enemy directly.
敵と一戦交えるより
苦しいものと覚悟しておけ
ウッ…
（尾平）どうした？ 昂
What's wrong, Ang?
大丈夫か？ 顔色が真っ青だぞ
You okay? You look pale as a ghost.
だ… 大丈夫
I-I'm okay.
More are coming!
（地響き）
また来たぞ　隠れろ
Hide!
T-This is to become warrior class!
し… 士族になるためだ
I'm... gonna become warrior class and make my mom who raised me on her own happy!
おいら 士族になって―
おいらを女手ひとつで育ててくれた
母ちゃんを幸せにするんだ
Ang...
昂…
どうだ？ 王賁　お前ら玉鳳隊に
ここまでやる根性あるか？
How about that, Wang Ben?
Does your Yufeng Unit have the guts to go this far?
Once they get past us,
あいつらをやり過ごしたら
一気に 敵の本陣に突撃だ
we're gonna charge straight for the enemy headquarters!
What's wrong?
（騎兵Ｂ）どうした？
There seems to be something moving over there.
（騎兵Ａ）
あの辺で 何か動いたように見えた
Hey, you!
（騎兵Ａ）おい お前たち
Go check and see if there are any survivors!
（騎兵Ｂ）生き残っている者が
いないか 確かめてこい
Yes, sir!
ンンッ… マジかよ
Are you kidding me?
What do we do?
どうする？
いっそ ここで一戦交えるか？
Do we just fight them here?
No, we just let them pass.
（渕(えん)）
いや このまま やり過ごすんだ
If we're seen here, everything goes up in smoke.
ここで見つかっては 全て水の泡
本陣を奇襲することができなくなる
We won't be able to launch a surprise attack on the headquarters.
Also, with all the corpses here...
（沛浪(はいろう)）
それに これだけの数の屍だ
those Wei guys are only going to
stab a small portion of us.
魏のヤツらが突き刺して歩くのは
ほんの一部
Yeah, there's no way in hell we'd end up being...
そうそう俺たちが刺されるわけが…
A-Ang!
こ… 昂が…
Run, Ang!
逃げろ 昂！
No! If I move now, they'll know about our plan!
ダメだ… ここで おいらが動いたら
作戦がバレちまう
Ang!
昂！
母ちゃん！
Mom!
What did you find?
（騎兵Ｂ）どうだ？
Sir!
（歩兵）はっ！
生き残っている者はいないようです
There doesn't seem to be any survivors!
I see. Perhaps it was just my imagination.
（騎兵Ａ）そうか 気のせいか
Let's go!
行くぞ！
Ang...
（尾平）昂…
The Yufeng Unit is coming!
（守備隊長）玉鳳隊が来るぞ！
We must not let them reach the headquarters!
本陣に行かせるわけには いかん
ここで食い止めろ！
Stop them!
S-Stop!
（魏兵）と… 止めろ！
（番陽）ヌハハハッ！
今度の敵も軽かったですな 賁さま
These enemies were a trifle as well, wouldn't you say, Lord Ben?!
Not yet!
まだだ　敵の大将の首を取るまでは
気を緩めるな！
We cannot relax until we've taken the enemy general's head!
But, all that is left is to defeat the headquarters, isn't—
しかし
あとは もう本陣を落とすだけ
Looks like you're a tad bit too late, Yufeng Unit!
ひと足遅かったな 玉鳳隊
Incredible how even riding on those shiny new horses 'a yours, you were beaten to the punch by a bunch of ants like us?!
ピッカピカの馬に乗ってるくせに
アリンコの俺たちに
先を越されるなんて
Looks like that special military training didn't amount to much, eh?!
軍事の英才教育も
たかが知れてんなぁ！
Young Master Wang Ben!
王賁のお坊ちゃん フッ…
Wang
Ben
Again!
（秦兵Ａ）まただ！
The Yufeng Unit has taken the head of an enemy general once again!
また 玉鳳隊が敵将の首を取ったぞ
This time, the Feixin Unit has captured an enemy camp!
（秦兵Ｂ）
今度は 飛信隊が敵陣を落とした！
Those two 300-Man Units are incredible!
（秦兵Ｃ）
すごいぞ あの２つの三百人隊は！
They're rendering so many achievements it's like they're competing with each other!
競うように武功を上げまくっている
But, it looks like the Yufeng Unit is doing better, as expected.
（秦兵Ａ）
しかし やはり玉鳳隊のほうが上だ
あの完全武装の騎馬隊は
そこらの千人隊より強力だぞ
That fully-armored mounted unit is stronger than most of the 1000-Man units around here.
（秦兵Ｂ）
いや 飛信隊だって負けては いない
No. The Feixin Unit still isn't losing to them.
あいつらは ほかの部隊には
決してできない危険な作戦を―
They've been coolly executing dangerous strategies that no other unit can pull off.
平気で やってのける
（蒙恬(もうてん)）へ～え… ここは また
随分と盛り上がってるみたいだな
This place looks pretty stirred up, too.
A new unit called the Feixin Unit and the Yufeng Unit have been competing for military accomplishments, it seems.
（じい）飛信隊という新参の部隊と
玉鳳隊が武功を争っておるようです
It's quite amusing that Wang Ben isn't able to hog all the achievements to himself.
（陸仙(りくせん)）
あの王賁が 武功を独占せずに
手を焼いているとは面白い
いかがでしょう？
What do you say?
Shall our Yuehua Unit join this war?
( The characters in Yueha mean happy/ease and magnificence. Yufeng means jade/king and Fenghuang, a phoenix-like mythical bird. )
我ら楽華(がくか)隊も この戦に
参戦するというのは
Yuehua Unit
Lord Meng Tian!
（じい･陸仙）蒙恬さま
Meng Tian
Qin Army Special 300-Man Unit
Yueha Unit 300-Man General
Nah.
（蒙恬）ヤ～ダよ
（じい･陸仙）ええっ！
I don't really like Wang Ben.
俺 王賁 苦手だし
第一 暑っ苦しいじゃん
And most of all, it's hot as hell out here.
こんな狭いとこで
あいつらと競り合うの
Way too hot to compete with those guys in a cramped place like this.
おお さすがです！
Impeccable judgement!
若は もっと大きな目で
戦を捉えておられるのですな？
You youngsters always grasp the big picture of a battle.
じいは うれしゅうございます…
This old man is beside himself.
You don't need to cry.
（蒙恬）泣かなくていいから…
そのようなお考えであれば
我ら楽華隊は―
In that line of thinking, we, the Yueha Unit, are quite suited to you, Lord Meng Tian.
蒙恬さまに ふさわしい
もっと大きな戦場を探しましょう
Let's look for a larger battlefield!
ていうか―
Well, uh...
この三百人隊が
やる気をなくさせるんですけど
These 300-Man Units are making me lose my motivation.
I just got that achievement in the war with Han the other day.
俺って
この間の韓(かん)との戦で 手柄を立てて
千人将に昇格したはずなんだよね
（陸仙）確かに…
I should've been promoted to a 1000-Man General.
You have a point.
しかし 白老さまが“あと１年は
三百人将で経験を積め”と
But, Lord Bai Lao said for you to gain another years' experience as a 300-Man General.
We cannot go against Lord Bai Lao's orders.
白老さまの命令に逆らうわけには…
That grandfather of mine sure is harsh in spite of being family.
身内には異常に厳しいよな
うちのじいさまは
かわいそうな俺
Poor me.
I feel such pity for you!
おいたわしや 若…
（蒙恬）だから泣かなくていいって
I told you, you don't need to cry.
Shall we get going?
行こっか
（じい･陸仙）はっ！
Yes, sir!
If we go South from here, we'll reach the front-most line where an even larger battle is unfolding.
（陸仙）ここから南に向かうと―
更に大きな戦が繰り広げられている
最前線がありますので―
So let us head for there!
そこへ まいりましょう
Naw.
（蒙恬）いや その前に
どっか にぎやかな町に行く
How 'bout before that, we go to some busy town.
To go shopping.
買い物に
（じい･陸仙）え～っ！
It has been two years since the last of the Six Great Generals,
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
かつて 秦国が誇った六大将軍
最後の１人 王騎が死して２年
that the State of Qin once took great pride in, Wang Qi, died.
Wang Ben of the Yufeng Unit,
玉鳳隊の王賁
Meng Tian of the Yueha Unit,
楽華隊の蒙恬
and Xin of the Feixin Unit.
そして 飛信隊の信
秦国の新たな時代の
大将軍を目指す若者たちが―
These young ones seeking to become the Great Generals of a new age steadily sprout,
今 着実に芽を出し
更なる成長を遂げるべく―
and are actively fighting on battlefields to achieve even greater growth.
戦場で躍動していた
Meanwhile, even at the State of Qin's capital, Xiangyang,
そのころ 秦国の都 咸陽(かんよう)でも
巨大な勢力が動きだそうとしていた
a gigantic power was about to start moving.
There is a report that the number of dependents gathered under Lü Buwei has finally reached 1,000 people.
（廷臣Ａ）
呂不韋(りょふい)のもとに集まった食客は―
ついに
1,000人に達したという報告がある
I've also heard that in the area of territory he governs, has over 100,000 farm families living there.
（廷臣Ｂ）治めている農地に暮らす
農民たちの数も10万戸を超えたとか
He is no longer merely one retainer.
もはや
ひとりの臣下という規模ではない
Moreover, by forming the alliance with Zhao,
（廷臣Ｃ）加えて
趙(ちょう)との間に同盟を結んだことが―
一段と ヤツの評価を上げている
his value was increased one level higher.
And Lü Buwei will only get greater.
（廷臣Ａ）
まだまだ呂不韋は大きくなるぞ
For Lü Buwei's camp,
（廷臣Ｂ）呂不韋の陣営にとって
我々 大王派をつぶすとは―
crushing us, the King Faction,
武力で皆殺しにすることではない
will not be a slaughter done by military force.
一方的な勢力図を作って
こちらを弱らせ
They're creating a one-sided power map, weakening us,
最後に残った数人の側近を抹殺して
大王を無力にするということだ
and finally obliterating the few close aides remaining in order to make his majesty powerless.
What we must do, is truly the opposite of that.
（廷臣Ｃ）そして 我々が
やらねばならぬのは正に その逆
We must repaint the power map within the palace in the colors of our King Faction.
結局は 王宮内の勢力図を―
我々 大王派の色に
塗り替えていくしかない
We're all well aware of that!
（壁(へき)）そのようなことは
とうに分かっている
だからこそ殿は治水工事に尽力して
実績を積み重ねているのだ
That is why my lord is working so hard at the
flood-control works, to build up achievements.
But that simply is not enough.
（廷臣Ａ）
だが それだけでは不十分だ
中立の立場を守っている者たちを
引き込むには―
In order to win over those still maintaining a neutral stance,
we need a much grander strategy!
もっと大きな戦略が必要なのだ
Then realistically, what sort of strategy could we use—
（壁）
では 現実に どのような戦略が…
What is it, Shi Shi?
（政(せい)）どうした？ 肆氏(しし)
なぜ黙っている？
Why are you keeping so quiet?
Wasn't it you that called this meeting today?
今日の会議を呼びかけたのは
お前のはずだが
Well, my king...
（肆氏）
では 恐れながら申し上げます
I must humbly apologize.
As it has been discussed, in order to put pressure on Lü Buwei's faction
今も議論されたとおり―
呂不韋の陣営を抑え
我々 大王派が実権を握るには―
and for the King Faction to grab hold of actual power,
王宮内の勢力図を
塗り替えねばなりませぬ
we must repaint the power map inside the royal palace.
The quickest way to do so would be to make an ally of even greater power.
そのために 最も手っとり早いのは
大勢力を味方につけること
But starting with you, the remnants of Jie Shi's faction have now almost completely joined our side.
しかし そなたをはじめ―
竭氏(けつし)の残党を
あらかた こちらに加えた今
一気に
勢力を逆転させるほどの勢力など
There is no force in Xiangyang great enough to suddenly cause a reversal of power.
この咸陽には存在しないであろう
（肆氏）いや 存在する
No, there is.
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）ハッ…
Among the people here, there are both those that know of it and dare not speak of it,
（肆氏）ここにいる人間の中にも
知っていて
あえて 口に出さない者や―
as well as those not aware of it at all.
全く気づいていない者がいるが
But here in Xiangyang, in addition to Lü Buwei's camp and the King Faction,
この咸陽には 呂不韋の陣営とも
我々 大王派のとも別の―
“第３勢力”が確かに存在している
there exists a third power.
あの呂不韋でさえ
手を出しあぐねている強大な勢力が
A great power that even Lü Buwei cannot get his hands on!
Stop this, Shi Shi!
やめよ 肆氏
You are sitting before his highness!
大王さまの御前であるぞ
そもそも あそこには
我々とて 立ち入ることができぬ
That is a place where we cannot intrude to begin with.
You are indeed correct, yet...
（肆氏）確かに そのとおりだが…
What if the other side has been in contact with them?
向こうから
接触してきたとしたら どうだ？
What happened, Shi Shi?
（政）何があったのだ？ 肆氏
The truth is... last night...
実は昨夜…
私の屋敷に現れたのです
They appeared... at my residence...
Messengers from that castle.
かの城より使者が
Wh-Why are you... here?!
（肆氏）な… なぜ―
そなたたちが ここに？
Shi Shi...
（趙高(ちょうこう)）
肆氏よ　そなたに この書簡を
We bring you this letter.
Th-The sovereign seal?!
ぎょ… 玉璽(ぎょくじ)
Did you say the sovereign seal?!
（廷臣Ｂ）玉璽だと？ 何をバカな
What is this?
王の印である玉璽は
当然 大王のもとにある
The symbol of the king, the sovereign seal, rests with his highness.
In some place his highness is not aware of,
大王のあずかり知れぬ所で―
玉璽を押された書簡が
発せられるなど ありえぬわ！
a letter was sent with the sovereign seal pressed to it?! Impossible!
What is going on here?!
（廷臣Ｃ）一体 どういうことだ！
（肆氏）先に 大王の弟君
成蟜(せいきょう)さまが反乱を起こされた折
Earlier, when a rebellion was started by his majesty's younger brother, Chengjiao...
When his majesty fled Xiangyang, the sovereign seal was hidden at a certain location.
大王は 咸陽を脱出されるに際して
玉璽をある場所に隠され
当時 成蟜派だった私は
ついに それを発見できなかった
As a member of the Chengjiao Faction at the time, I was never able to find it.
That is because it was hidden with the third power I have been speaking of.
それは 今言っている第３の勢力の
中に隠されたからだ
Are you saying that after the rebellion was suppressed, before it was returned,
反乱を平定した俺に玉璽を返す前に
複製を作られたということか？
they made a duplicate of it?
This is desecration!
冒涜(ぼうとく)だ！ 玉璽の複製など
国家に対する反逆罪
Making a duplicate of the sovereign seal is an act of treason to the kingdom!
A crime deserving of death!
万死に値する悪行です！
先ほどから
何の話をしているのですか？
Anyhow, what have all of you been talking about?
What is this third power?
第３の勢力とは…
そんなものが
この咸陽に存在するなどとは―
I have never heard of any such a power existing here in Xiangyang.
聞いたことがありません！
（昌文君）いや 壁
No, Bi...
You are aware of that power.
お前は その勢力を知っている
You have just been distracted by its foreignness.
ただ
その存在の異質さに気を取られ
You simply have not realized that it is related to our struggle for power.
我らの勢力争いに関わる存在だと
気づいていないだけだ
Although it is located in Xiangyang,
そこは 咸陽にありながら
いかなる要人も―
it is in a closed-off castle that no one may enter regardless of their importance.
足を踏み入れることすら
許されぬ閉ざされた城
（宦官(かんがん)）低頭！
Bow down!
You mustn't raise your head up, Xiang!
（陽(よう)）絶対に
頭を上げちゃダメだよ 向(こう)ちゃん…
（向）わ… 分かってるよ 陽ちゃん
I-I know, Yang!
A castle made up of over 1,000 court ladies and countless eunuchs.
（昌文君）1,000人を超える宮女と
無数の宦官からなる城
宮女たちのほとんどが
国内外の名門の出であり―
The palace maids almost all come from noble families both domestic and foreign.
その背後に 有力者の勢力と
野望が うごめいている
Behind them lurks someone with great power and ambition.
それらを束ねたならば…
Together, they form a castle of women that holds an immense power, the harem.
絶大な力を擁する女の城 後宮
そして その女の城の主(あるじ)は
現在の秦国太后(たいこう)さま
The master of that women's castle is the current Queen Dowager of the State of Qin.
In other words, the third force is...
つまり―
第３の勢力とは
大王さまのお母上の勢力だ
the power of his majesty's mother!
Beautiful Venom
End